HELEN BONILLA GONZALEZ

Front-End Developer - UI/UX Designer

Santiago de Cali, Valle | +57 3127416736 | helenbonillag@gmail.com



CAREER SUMMARY:

Systems Engineer, with outstanding ability to adapt technical knowledge to customer needs, where the focus on design and usability can contribute to optimize the performance of an application. I am a creative person who is proactive, motivated by being in contact with new technologies and with experience working in large teams.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Freelance

Front-end Developer & UI/UX Designer | January 2024 - Present

- Built and maintained websites for clients through various online platforms
- Assisted troubleshooting software.
- Created and tested applications for websites.
- Filed reports, gathered information, and performed research.

Quipux

Requirements Analyst | January 2023 - December 2023

- Deep understanding of the user and their needs.
- Creating user flows and wireframes to plan the structure of the product.
- Creating attractive and visually pleasing interfaces.
- Design interface elements for further development.

Project Red Aprende Mintic - Universidad del valle

UI/UX Designer | June 2019 - January 2020

- Participation in meetings with the user, where the specifications of the study environment are established.
- Designing the application interface.
- Planning and conducting user tests to obtain valuable feedback.

NOTABLE PROJECTS:

- Project Mintic RedAprende: https://redaprende.colombiaaprende.edu.co/
- Portfolio: https://github.com/HelenBonilla

EDUCATION:

2019 - 2023 | Universidad del valle Computer Science Engineering

2022 | Udemy Academy

UX Design: User Experience UX/UI + Figma

2020 | CertiProf

Scrum Fundation Professional Certificate (SFPC)

2020 | SENA

Quality in software development

SOFT SKILLS:

- Adaptability / Leadership
- Self-taught / Recursion
- Assertive communication
- Teamwork / Pragmatic thinking
- · Critical thinking / Empathy
- Collaboration

SKILLS:

- Javascript / React / Typescript
- Html / Css / bootstrap
- Git / Github / Gitlab
- Jira / Trello
- Figma / Adobe XD
- Google Analytics
- Adobe Creative / Canva
- SQL / Posgresql
- Front-end web development
- Code structure and architecture
- Web Design optimization
- Programming languages

LANGUAGES:

- English B2 (Conversational)
- Spanish (Native)